Matej Ciglenečki

Software engineer with over one year of experience, highly interested in computer science, software engineering, and machine learning. I'm a strong communicator who can present findings clearly and understandably. Throughout my work and academic experience, I've developed excellent problem-solving capabilities accompanied by a strong sense of ownership. I'm fascinated by well-written libraries, software modularity, and design principles.

Zagreb, Croatia matej.ciglenecki@gmail.com +385 91 6133 168 github.com/ciglenecki linkedin.com/in/matej-ciglenečki

Education

M.Sc Data Science – Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Computing, Zagreb, Croatia relevant courses: Advanced Algorithms and Data Structures, Advanced Operating Systems, Parallel Computing, Business Intelligence, Numerical Mathematics, Machine Learning, Technology Entrepreneurship

Oct 2021 – July 2023 (expected)

B.Sc Computer Science – <u>Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Computing</u>, Zagreb, Croatia relevant courses: Algorithms and Data Structures, Object Oriented Programming, Design Patterns, Databases, Probability and Statistics, Communication Networks, Network Programming

Oct 2017 - July 2021

Experience

Photomath - Software Engineer Intern

July 2022 - Oct 2022

 Developed and deployed cloud services that parse, transform, enrich and deliver millions of events used for verifying Photomath's core regression tests (Python, GCP, Datastream, Pub/Sub, Dataflow, Cloud Run, GitHub Actions).

Memgraph - Software Engineer

Oct 2020 - Oct 2021

- Designed a PostgreSQL database schema and wrote feature specifications for Memgraph Cloud platform.
 After the successful implementation, the platform achieved 300% user growth in the first month.
- Implemented Memgraph Cloud's backend (node.js, TypeScript, Express, Sequelize, PostgreSQL) that supports 400+ active users, manages AWS EC2 instances, and supports monthly user billing based on user usage.
- Set up Elastic Stack on AWS EC2 to analyze application logs (AWS CloudWatch) in Kibana dashboards.
- · Wrote unit and integration tests for Memgraph Cloud's backend (Jest).
- · Wrote educational lessons and created graph datasets (Memgraph, Cypher).

Memgraph - Software Engineer Intern

July 2020 - Oct 2020

- Implemented geographic graph data visualization in Memgraph Lab (TypeScript, Leaflet).
- Refactored codebase via design patterns (TypeScript, Angular).
- Wrote a <u>summary blog post</u>.

Skills

Languages: Python, TypeScript, C++, C, R, SQL, bash

Technologies: git, NumPy, PostgreSQL, Linux, Docker, Elastic Stack, GCP, AWS, node.js, express.js, FastAPI
Other: Data structures, Algorithms, OOP, Design patterns, Operating systems, Machine learning, Statistics

Workshops and projects

LUMEN Data science competition – GeoGuesser AI Agent

2022

- · Led a finalist team of three. The goal was to predict the location of 64 000 Google Street View images in Croatia.
- Achieved 2nd place in model performance with a mean error of 22km, measured as the great-circle distance from the true to the predicted location.
- Used **Python**, **PyTorch**, deep learning, geospatial feature engineering and computer vision methods to transform geographic data, process images, train multiple models and predict locations of unseen Google Street View images.
- Implemented a FastAPI server that allows inference on a trained model.
- Wrote project documentation and technical documentation.

Implementation of driver fatigue detection in an EEG-based system - Data Science course project

2022

- Successfully reproduced results and methods described in the research article with Python.
- · Performed data analysis and feature extraction on driver's EEG data. Processed 7200 seconds worth of EEG data.
- Trained 4 different models, successfully predicted driver's fatigue with scikit-learn with +99% accuracy, and achieved 1% better results compared to the research article.

Al BattleGround hackaton - Al Agent

2022

• Worked in a team of four. Implemented a software agent in **Python** which plays against other agents in a turn-based game. Agents communicate via a streaming protocol, and based on the game's state the agent tries to perform the optimal move (attack, switch characters, or use an item). The game consists of multiple different characters, actions, and modifiers.

Student success analysis - Statistical Data Analysis course project

2022

- Led a team of 4 in the Statistical Data Analysis course project written in R.
- Analyzed student success data with the following statistical methods: t-tests, chi-squared test, Fischer's test, normality tests, f-tests, ANOVA, and linear regression.
- · Wrote a final report which describes the theory and the context of used statistical methods used in the project.

Soft skills academy - leadership group

2020

AG04 - Spring Boot Summer School

2019

Developed a web application with Java Spring in a group of 5 and completed a Java Spring course.